Prince Odame

Backend Software Engineer

opodame@gmail.com

+233501377957/+4542901178

in linkedin.com/in/prince-odame

princeodame.com



github.com/Odame

I am a self-motivated backend software engineer with over 6 years of experience who is well-versed in RESTful APIs with microservices architecture. I designed highly scalable backend systems that scaled to millions of users for my company.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Backend Engineer @ Blue Ocean Robotics

Jan 2020 - Present | Odense, Denmark

Building robust cloud based solutions across several portfolio such as Beam Robot, UVD Robots and PTR Robots.

Senior Backend Engineer @ SchoolDesk

Sept 2017 - 2019 | Accra, Ghana

- ▶ Built the entire backend for a startup (SchoolDesk), with a team of other engineers, using Python & Flask.
- Works with a variety of languages, frameworks and platforms such as Javascript, Python, Flask, Node and Google Cloud Platform.
- Split an initially monolith backend into decoupled microservices that serve different aspects of the system, including mobile apps.
- Write high quality, documented and maintainable code using SOLID principles for quick/easier on-boarding on the backend team.
- Set up CI/CD with Gitlab for quick and safe deployments.

Onsite IT Support @ Schlumberger

Sept 2017 - April 2018 | Takoradi, Ghana

- Provide IT support to employees of Schlumberger via HelpDesk.
- Deployed and managed network systems, ensuring close to 100% uptime throughout the period.
- Interact with the members of IT support team in other locations, leveraging office collaborating tools like MS Teams, MS Planner and Skype for Business

Backend Developer @ ASQII

Jan - Oct 2017 | Remote

- Design structure for backend of several in-house and clients applications.
- Implemented systems mainly in Python, hosted on Amazon Web Services.
- Collaborate with other remote team members using tools like Slack, Trello.

Android Developer @ ASQII

May - Dec 2016 | Remote

- Development of native apps for the android platform using Java.
- Reduced battery usage of existing apps by ~35%, by leveraging Google's recommended development patterns for android platform.
- Redesign existing app using Material Design principles.
- Built apps that integrates with Firebase Realtime Database and takes advantage of other serverless features such as Firebase Authentication for Social Auth (Facebook, Twitter) and Firebase Cloud Messaging.

System/Database Administrator @ OWASS Basic School

May 2015 - June 2017 | Kumasi, Ghana

- Developed an on-premise Windows desktop application for managing students records stored in MS SQL Server database.
- Leverage Visual C# to design custom UI components for school.
- Implemented a service in C#.NET which periodically creates and uploads data backups to an online server application hosted on Heroku.
- Reduced institution's expenses by \sim 1.3% through digitisation.

Volunteer Trainer @ Ghana Robotics Academy Foundation

June 2014 - June 2018 | Kumasi, Ghana

Trained high school students in robotics and other STEM fields.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python, Javascript

Java, Golang, C#, VB, C/C++

Libraries & Frameworks

Flask, Node.JS, Express.JS Django, React

Data

MySQL, MongoDB, MS SQL Server PostgreSQL, GraphQL, ElasticSearch

Tools & Platforms

MQTT, Docker, AWS, GCP, Heroku, Git, RabbitMQ, TDD

EDUCATION

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology

2013-2017 | Kumasi, Ghana

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering.

Majors in Software Engineering.

Courses: Data Structures & Algorithms, VLSI, Computer Architecture, Robotics, Distributed Systems Design, Object Oriented Programming, Computer

Graphics, Statistics & Probability.

PROJECTS

mqtt-sub-router

github.com/Odame/mqtt-sub-router A subscription-based router for mgtt client. Built for NodeJS environment.

gae-env

github.com/Odame/gae-env

A python package that allows for secure storage of environment variables in Cloud Datastore for Google Appengine projects.

loggabat

github.com/jaxtisapia/loggabat

Javascript logger for filtering logs you need in production, from logs you need in development mode only.

Robotic Lawn Mower

A lawn mower that can operate autonomously to clear a predefined piece of lawn. Written in C/C++

INTERESTS

Robotics, STEM Education, AI/ML